[
    {
        "question": "فَإِذَا",
        "answer": "So when",
        "pcklId": "398",
        "rootWordId": 27,
        "tlit": "fa-idhā",
        "frequency": "409",
        "surahnum": "94",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِذَا فَرَغْتَ فَانْصَبْ",
        "rootWord": "إِذَا",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "إِذَا",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idhā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الَّذِي",
        "answer": "Which",
        "pcklId": "1424",
        "rootWordId": 59,
        "tlit": "alladhī",
        "frequency": "1464",
        "surahnum": "94",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِي أَنْقَضَ ظَهْرَكَ",
        "rootWord": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "waznEnglish": "who, which, that",
        "waznTlit": "alladhī",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Relative pronoun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَإِلَىٰ",
        "answer": "And to",
        "pcklId": "740",
        "rootWordId": 63,
        "tlit": "wa-ilā",
        "frequency": "742",
        "surahnum": "94",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِلَىٰ رَبِّكَ فَارْغَبْ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَىٰ",
        "rootWordType": "preposition",
        "wazn": "إِلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to, toward, until",
        "waznTlit": "ilā",
        "waznType": "Preposition"
    },
    {
        "question": "ذِكْرَكَ",
        "answer": "your reputation",
        "pcklId": "271",
        "rootWordId": 511,
        "tlit": "dhik'raka",
        "frequency": "292",
        "surahnum": "94",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَرَفَعْنَا لَكَ ذِكْرَكَ",
        "rootWord": "ذ ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ذِكْر",
        "waznEnglish": "Remember",
        "waznTlit": "dhik'r",
        "waznType": "Verbal noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبِّكَ",
        "answer": "your Lord",
        "pcklId": "959",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbika",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "94",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِلَىٰ رَبِّكَ فَارْغَبْ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَارْغَبْ",
        "answer": "turn your attention",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 566,
        "tlit": "fa-ir'ghab",
        "frequency": "8",
        "surahnum": "94",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِلَىٰ رَبِّكَ فَارْغَبْ",
        "rootWord": "ر غ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَرْغَبُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to desire, to prefer",
        "waznTlit": "yarghabu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَرَفَعْنَا",
        "answer": "And We raised high",
        "pcklId": "21",
        "rootWordId": 573,
        "tlit": "warafaʿnā",
        "frequency": "29",
        "surahnum": "94",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَرَفَعْنَا لَكَ ذِكْرَكَ",
        "rootWord": "ر ف ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَفَعَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to raise",
        "waznTlit": "rafaʿa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَشْرَحْ",
        "answer": "We expanded",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 764,
        "tlit": "nashraḥ",
        "frequency": "5",
        "surahnum": "94",
        "ayahnum": "1",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " أَلَمْ نَشْرَحْ لَكَ صَدْرَكَ",
        "rootWord": "ش ر ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ش ر ح",
        "waznEnglish": "to expand, to open",
        "waznTlit": "shīn rā ḥā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "صَدْرَكَ",
        "answer": "your breast",
        "pcklId": "43",
        "rootWordId": 827,
        "tlit": "ṣadraka",
        "frequency": "46",
        "surahnum": "94",
        "ayahnum": "1",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " أَلَمْ نَشْرَحْ لَكَ صَدْرَكَ",
        "rootWord": "ص د ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صَدْر",
        "waznEnglish": "will proceed",
        "waznTlit": "ṣadr",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "ظَهْرَكَ",
        "answer": "your back",
        "pcklId": "40",
        "rootWordId": 945,
        "tlit": "ẓahraka",
        "frequency": "59",
        "surahnum": "94",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِي أَنْقَضَ ظَهْرَكَ",
        "rootWord": "ظ ه ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ظَهْر",
        "waznEnglish": "(is) apparent",
        "waznTlit": "ẓahr",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْعُسْرِ",
        "answer": "the hardship",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 986,
        "tlit": "l-ʿus'ri",
        "frequency": "12",
        "surahnum": "94",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِنَّ مَعَ الْعُسْرِ يُسْرًا",
        "rootWord": "ع س ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عُسْر",
        "waznEnglish": "you disagree",
        "waznTlit": "ʿus'r",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْعُسْرِ",
        "answer": "the hardship",
        "pcklId": "5",
        "rootWordId": 986,
        "tlit": "l-ʿus'ri",
        "frequency": "12",
        "surahnum": "94",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ مَعَ الْعُسْرِ يُسْرًا",
        "rootWord": "ع س ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عُسْر",
        "waznEnglish": "you disagree",
        "waznTlit": "ʿus'r",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَرَغْتَ",
        "answer": "you have finished",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 1123,
        "tlit": "faraghta",
        "frequency": "6",
        "surahnum": "94",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِذَا فَرَغْتَ فَانْصَبْ",
        "rootWord": "ف ر غ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فَرَغْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to finish",
        "waznTlit": "faragh",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَانْصَبْ",
        "answer": "then labor hard",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 1474,
        "tlit": "fa-inṣab",
        "frequency": "32",
        "surahnum": "94",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِذَا فَرَغْتَ فَانْصَبْ",
        "rootWord": "ن ص ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نُصِبَتْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be fixed, to labour",
        "waznTlit": "nuṣibat",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَنْقَضَ",
        "answer": "weighed upon",
        "pcklId": "6",
        "rootWordId": 1510,
        "tlit": "anqaḍa",
        "frequency": "9",
        "surahnum": "94",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِي أَنْقَضَ ظَهْرَكَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ق ض",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَنقَضَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to weigh",
        "waznTlit": "anqaḍa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وِزْرَكَ",
        "answer": "your burden",
        "pcklId": "19",
        "rootWordId": 1605,
        "tlit": "wiz'raka",
        "frequency": "27",
        "surahnum": "94",
        "ayahnum": "2",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَوَضَعْنَا عَنْكَ وِزْرَكَ",
        "rootWord": "و ز ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وِزْر",
        "waznEnglish": "they bear",
        "waznTlit": "wiz'r",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَوَضَعْنَا",
        "answer": "And We removed",
        "pcklId": "20",
        "rootWordId": 1621,
        "tlit": "wawaḍaʿnā",
        "frequency": "26",
        "surahnum": "94",
        "ayahnum": "2",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَوَضَعْنَا عَنْكَ وِزْرَكَ",
        "rootWord": "و ض ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وَضَعَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to deliver, to give birth",
        "waznTlit": "waḍaʿa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يُسْرًا",
        "answer": "(is) ease",
        "pcklId": "24",
        "rootWordId": 1658,
        "tlit": "yus'ran",
        "frequency": "44",
        "surahnum": "94",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِنَّ مَعَ الْعُسْرِ يُسْرًا",
        "rootWord": "ي س ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يُسْر",
        "waznEnglish": "We (have) made it easy",
        "waznTlit": "yus'r",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "يُسْرًا",
        "answer": "(is) ease",
        "pcklId": "25",
        "rootWordId": 1658,
        "tlit": "yus'ran",
        "frequency": "44",
        "surahnum": "94",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ مَعَ الْعُسْرِ يُسْرًا",
        "rootWord": "ي س ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يُسْر",
        "waznEnglish": "We (have) made it easy",
        "waznTlit": "yus'r",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    }
]